Guide to the De Forest Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
De Forest family papers
1798-1889
1798-1825
MS 177
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4.5
The papers consist of correspondence, account books, journals, letterbooks, financial records, and related papers of David Curtis De Forest and family members. The papers document the business and political careers of De Forest, including his commercial enterprise in Buenos Aires, Argentina. Correspondence, located within journals and letterbooks, includes letters written to family members, colleagues, and associates while on sea voyages to South America and elsewhere.
De Forest family
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Frederick Hill, 1939, and gift of Clementine De Forest Griffin, 1940.
Arrangement
Arranged in four series: I. David Curtis De Forest, 1798-1825. II. William B. De Forest, 1861-1873. III. George Butler Griffin, 1857-1889. IV. Family Papers.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of the account books, journals, letterbooks, financial records, and related papers of David Curtis De Forest (1774-1825), William B. De Forest, George Butler Griffin, and other family members. David Curtis De Forest files include documentation on his service as United States consul general to Argentina.
Biographical / Historical
David Curtis De Forest was born January 10, 1774 in Huntington, Connecticut. He worked on sailing vessels as a young man and served as a lieutenant in the army (1799-1801). De Forest established the first American commercial house in Buenos Aires, Argentina. Political and military unrest in Argentina (1811-1817) did not harm his business, and De Forest was commissioned as consul general to the United States by the new Argentine Republic (1815). De Forest resigned this position before receiving any U.S. diplomatic papers. De Forest died on February 22, 1825 in New Haven, Connecticut.
Voyages and travels; Argentina -- History -- War of Independence, 1810-1817; South America; Butler, George Griffin; De Forest, David Curtis, 1774-1825; De Forest, William B.; Edwards, Pierpont, 1750-1826; De Forest family
- DAVID CURTIS DE FOREST (1774-1825), 1798-1825; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains material arranged alphabetically by record type, with "Argentine financial records" organized at the end of the series.
  - Account book, 1819-1825 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Commonplace book, 1799-1802 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Gardening book, 1819-1824 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Journals
    - No. 1, 1800-1801 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - No. 2, 1801-1803 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - No. 3, 1803-1804 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - No. 4, 1804-1805 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - No. 5, 1805-1806 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - No. 6, 1806-1809 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - No. 8, 1809-1817 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Letterbooks
    - No. 1, 1798-1799 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - No. 2, 1805-1806 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - No. 3, 1806-1809 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - No. 4, 1809-1811 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - No. 5, 1811-1816 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - No. 6, 1818-1819 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - No. 7, 1819-1821 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - No. 8, 1821-1825 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Typescripts, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Notes
    - Commerce, 1803-1807 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Tour of the West, 1822 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Argentine financial records
    - Cash book, 1816-1818 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Journal, 1814-1816 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Journal, 1814-1816 (Box 6A, Folder 24)
    - Ledger, 1814-1816 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Wastebook, 1814-1816 (Box 7A, Folder 26)
- WILLIAM B. DE FOREST, 1861-1873; Series II
  This series is arranged alphabetically by record type.
  - Commonplace book, undated (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Estate journal: Russel C. Abernathy, 1861-1873 (Box 8, Folder 28)
- GEORGE BUTLER GRIFFIN, 1857-1889; Series III
  - Catalogue: personal library, 1889 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Logbook: U.S. States Surveying Expedition, 1857-1858, 1857-1859 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Notebook: genealogy of Griswold family, 1884-1885 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Scrapbook: Spanish articles on Colombia, 1869-1875 (Box 9, Folder 32)
- FAMILY PAPERS, Series IV
  This series contains material arranged alphabetically by the name of the individual. Miscellaneous items are filed at the end of the series.
  - Canfield, M., undated (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - de Espril, Courtney Letts, undated (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - De Forest, John, undated (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - De Forest, Lockwood, undated (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Deal, Jana N., undated (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Everit, Annie E., undated (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Olmstead, Denison, undated (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Shepard, Charles U., undated (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Notebooks, undated (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Typescripts and photocopies, undated (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 11, Folder 44-45)